hey folks welcome to moment of clarity
thanks for joining me i got a huge show
for you a couple of great guests guests
i'm also live on rockfinrockfin.com
lee camp i'm at youtube.com moment of
clarity um but as you know
uh and we're gonna get into this this is
the show to talk about it uh as you know
my tv show of eight years uh canceled
due to ux sanctions all of the old
videos
on youtube all the past episodes
thousands of video clips all uh banned
globally and my podcast moment of
clarity deleted from spotify
but we're gonna address that uh today
and and creating the alternatives to
these big tech platforms that censor us
that uh try and make sure everyone is
giving in just just letting the us
propaganda wash over them and not
fighting back like some surly
so-and-so's how dare you so we're gonna
we're gonna get into that with uh two
great guests uh but before
that real quick just uh if you haven't
already become a member of
patreon.comcamp
also um after this i'm gonna talk about
how i'm starting a new show i'm starting
a new show with mint press and behind
the headlines
and uh i'm gonna tell you more about
that after we uh do the the interview
portion of the show but these two guests
uh incredible individuals in their own
right sean o'brien is
one of the top guys at panquake.com
pan quake is a new social media platform
that will be out soon you've heard me
talk about it before and john kiriakou
the uh the well-known cia whistleblower
revealed the u.s torture program also an
author and uh and a radio host and so
many other things so
let's talk with them hey guys
hey lee
hey happy to be here
thanks for joining me uh yeah these are
these are [__] crazy times but
you two are working on building
something positive out of all out of all
the rubble
um
i i guess uh let let's start i'm gonna
in a minute i'm gonna while we continue
to talk uh assuming i can get the
technology right we're gonna i'm gonna
show some of susie's video but uh
we'll we'll be talking over it so people
will get to see what pancake quake looks
like but i guess let's begin with uh
with why we need pan quake what talk
about the state of censorship right now
sure i think john actually would be the
best one to start on that especially
because you've experienced censorship
directly uh recently
yeah you know
who who would have ever thought that in
the united states we would have to deal
with some of these issues lee you know
it's honestly i'm not over using the
word but it's heartbreaking to me when i
hear you say things like you lost a
decade's worth of work and thousands of
of video clips thousands of hours of
work it's just gone
that's that's criminal that should never
happen in a place like the united states
every day i go to my own twitter uh
profile to see if
um if i've been tagged as an official
you know mouthpiece of the russian
government right which they which
they've done to like george galloway
who's right he's been not even connected
to rt anymore they've done it to ed
schultz even though he's been dead for
four years yep they did
they did and you know it occurred to to
so many of us
that we need to fix everything that we
complain about being broken on these
other uh sites i don't even want to say
their names because i don't want people
to go to them and uh and open new pages
but i mean we know the big ones uh
even when they change their names to
things that are supposed to sound
futuristic
they um they are not free they are not
fair they are not transparent and we
need a place to go where we can fix all
those different things that we complain
about you know make the perfect site and
honestly i think that's what this is
that's what pan quake is i had never
really heard of it until susie dawson
introduced me to it she mentioned it i
don't know maybe it was about a year ago
and i thought uh okay well you know
pancake rumble whatever parlor there are
a whole bunch of them
and then she and shawn actually showed
me a demo
and as a non-tech guy
it it
just blew my socks off
it was incredible
what were
what are some of the aspects you like
best about it well you know it depends
on what is
in what you're interested in
that
that will sort of guide you as to what's
the most important for me it was the
fact that there is no outside influence
there's no corporate money for example
there's no government money uh they
don't answer to anybody i absolutely
love the fact that it's based in in
iceland it's hosted in iceland
um there are no algorithms that are
going to push traffic um away from you
or
push uh paid advertisements to you
nothing at all like that it's it's
transparent it's real you can customize
it it's everything that that we've been
waiting for
so
sean tell us about the
the building of pan quake um it's been
going on for a while now uh tell us
about the process and what makes it you
know in the in the in the creation of it
what makes it different from so many of
the social media sites we use
so sure um as john mentioned um i don't
even really want to talk about uh those
other social media sites but it's worth
saying you know um we're not a twitter
killer twitter is the twitter killer
right um and what's going on right now
is those sites are self-destructing a
lot of the ways in which they do
business um are exactly the things we
won't do well when i said of a facebook
i guess they had some terrible uh
quarterly earnings recently or something
and uh i said at the time oh yeah they
lost like hundreds of billions of
dollars in a day or something and i said
at the time i was like well part of what
made facebook great was you could go
there for
information that was not on your
mainstream media that was not a
government outlet it was it was
alternative information coming that that
was allowed to come out and they've
spent the past several years i mean
because they're bending over backward
for the government but they've spent the
last couple years destroying
any alternative information so now okay
go to facebook and what get cnn anybody
can do that turning on their tv what
what are they getting from facebook they
couldn't get from turning on their tv
and you know what lee if i could
interrupt sean for one second i'm sorry
to interrupt you go for it
i used to do exactly the same thing with
twitter you know there were so many
alternative sites that that i wanted to
cover and i couldn't there weren't
enough hours in the day so what i did is
i followed the people whose opinions i
respected the most right the the the
ralph naders and environmental activists
and whistleblowers and and all these
people that i had
such respect for and then they would
post stuff from sites that i i know i
wouldn't have
checked i don't go to propublica every
day for example or to the the marshall
center or the brennan center or some of
these other important things i just
don't i don't think about it but they
did
well now so many of the sites that i
went to twitter and to facebook to read
things like telesur for example or rt
or sputnik or you know whatever they're
just they're banned they're banned
and in the case of press tv uh they're
like
band band where the fbi confiscated
their website and everything
they stole their website people thought
websites
and then put a comment like mocking them
we stole your website
so um you know this is gonna be this is
gonna be the one stop
that i'm gonna need to make i'll be able
to see what all those people i respect
are saying or thinking i'm not gonna
have to toggle all around the internet
hoping that i didn't miss something and
i'm not going to have to worry that some
corporate giant or government entity uh
blocked something that that he or she
just
decided i didn't need to see
that's right so i mean that's the first
thing right we're very serious about
freedom of information um we're a group
of folks many of us activists in this
area and in other areas right um making
sure that information uh flows can
happen
much in the way in which they used to
happen on the internet right um but
really trying to also come up with their
own unique features that allow
amplification in a way that no other
social network has done before
um we started this journey you know at
the end of january 2021 um
february to may 2021 we did the project
planning and the hiring and you know
sort of bootstrapping um the the uh
entity behind pan quake um which as john
explained is non-corporate no vc money
none of that um we began doing the
actual coding in june um and then by
august october december going fall into
winter we just kept doing more and more
proof of concept on the pieces of the
network and then we just uh unveiled um
a functioning interface
right and then the beauty the look and
feel that we just unveiled the other day
people really love it
that's all said that's really important
stuff we love that it looks good we love
that it's it's going to be fun to use we
love that people are going to want to be
there and want to share um but we're
also serious on the back end of having
technology that's censorship resistant
um part of that is a serious blockchain
back end
decentralization right so although we
have core infrastructure in iceland
we're also going to have decentralized
peer-to-peer communication between nodes
on the network and that's extremely
important to be resilient in this way
right um it take downs those kinds of
things ddosing those kinds of threats on
the network are um easier to do if you
have a
centralized uh you know cloud-based
thing right and we don't want to do a
centralized cloud-based thing we're
building something that's actually
peer-to-peer where um nodes on the
network aka users
people participating in the conversation
are actually directly connecting to each
other and verifying each other um as
pancake users so that's the first thing
no timeline manipulation right no
advertising
the timeline is a bottomless um you know
beautifully scrolling uh uh timeline
that just has new content showing up at
the top
and in terms of the no ads and that's
one of the things that i feel like it's
uh
gets glossed over but a lot of people
think oh ads are kind of annoying but
ads end up controlling the path of
you know not just social media sites but
so much in our culture where if you're
not selling enough ads then you you you
they're going to change their whole
system they'll they'll do anything to
make the ad buyers happy and you know
it's it's part of the reason you'll
never see cnn to uh do an anti-oil story
half their heads or oil companies so by
having no ads it's a huge difference
so it manipulates the conversation but
even worse than that as we know um it's
advertising surveillance on these other
networks right
these ads are studying you um literally
you're running code in the background
that's trying to personalize the
experience it's building these shadow
profiles um this is the kind of stuff of
course i do at yale privacy lab um we've
done years and years of digging into ad
brokers and not just uh on desktop you
know browser-based applications but also
mobile applications um they're atrocious
they study people and they often ally
these advertising brokers with
governments um government spies
specifically and you know every week
there's more and more disclosures around
that so not even allowing that avenue
you know not not having advertising not
manipulating trends um that is a very
special thing you're 100 right um and
we're very happy to have a simple
subscription model instead um
which is honest and you know more than
uh enough to make sure that we can keep
uh the ship sailing and really grow and
scale this network which is um really
incredible um the other thing i'll make
sure i say uh if folks go out to
pancreatic.com and check out the uh cool
new features we have amplification
features that
basically
not only are uh just our stuff invented
wholly by pancake specifically susie
dawson came up with this stuff um but
also are going to allow people to reach
their audience in a way that they
haven't before um one of them for
example is thunderquakes this allows you
to send a message to all of the people
following you
in the pan quake network
that message is basically an opt-in hey
you know i'm going to be
doing this show on next tuesday i'm
going to be sending out this message
this quake
would you like to amplify it would you
like to participate in this thunderquake
um so
those folks can opt in and then it goes
out
it's going to be a huge boon to have
that kind of thing for content creators
um and there's three other features and
i want to go into all of them if folks
go out to pancreate.com and watch the
video that lee you're showing in the
background here um
that all that will be explained to you
and it's really really cool stuff
i'm excited because folks like you lee
john other folks who have been just
booted off you know
you know real networks right network's
just shutting down overnight
you're going to have the ability to
reach your audience and know that you're
actually reaching them right now i'm
sure as you know if you do throw money
into the advertising pit that is a
facebook that is you know google um you
are going to not even know who you're
reaching right um you're going to
basically be wasting a huge amount of
that money
by not having advertising and instead
having honest amplification right and
making it fun and pleasant to be doing
that
we're going to have a totally different
environment and pan quake and we really
want content creators to be a part of
that so
what else is he missing john that you
that that makes you think it's uh
pancake can and will be different from
the social media dystopia where we're
stuck in
well sean's uh sean's a tech guy and i'm
not a tech guy and as someone who's not
a tech guy i can tell you it's
extraordinarily easy to understand
and and listen i'm not a kid anymore i'm
i'm 57 years old it it really i'm
embarrassed to say but it actually does
have to be dumbed down for somebody like
me this doesn't need to be dumbed down
it's perfect i i went to it i could
understand it i could use it i watched
the video i spoke with sean and and with
susie it was it was all
crystal clear it's very very easy to use
so there's no reason
that anybody should be intimidated by it
because it's new technology and it's
something that hasn't been done before
it was created with
ease of use in mind and that's why it's
going to be successful
when's it i know we've seen a demo uh
now that people can watch it at
pancake.com when's it when's it coming
out
so the answer that as it has been in the
past is it will come out when we reach
our funding goals right we're grassroots
funded we're running a crowdfunding
campaign um we need to get to the next
stage right and to finish this last
round of funding and when we do that
then we'll be able to you know bring on
the folks we need to um to launch the
beta um so the two things i'll say is
you reached out to the cia's venture
capital so
you tell me
not allowed believe me um
if we had that you know we would have
been launched uh in a week and uh we
certainly would be spying on everyone
which is yeah what these other sites do
and you joke but of course if you look
at the history of silicon valley these
these other sites these other social
media platforms they get money from
places like you know these um you know
venture capital firms associated with
the cia um
not to talk too much about that dirty
side of it because we're not doing that
um i also want to say we have free and
open source software i want to keep
emphasizing the open open source aspect
here um we will be releasing our source
code as well for the entire platform
that's a really important aspect it's
very near and dear to my heart from an
ethical standpoint but it also means you
know we'll have longevity and the
ability for pancreatic to live on far
beyond you know who knows what awful
things happening in the world um so
that's really a sustainability thing too
um but yeah if folks want to uh you know
help support us please go out and donate
you can donate in a number of
cryptocurrencies if you'd like to um so
you know there's a lot of different
options for you to be able to donate um
we also have a publication um called
talk liberation um that's a newsletter a
substance newsletter that's
non-paywalled
if you do decide to subscribe to that
for five dollars a month um that money
all of that money goes towards the pan
quake build um so that's also another
way to help us out and we do have also
applications open for the beta
that means folks can go out and apply to
be one of the first users in the beta
we basically have a system where we're
using um tokens and we are going through
the applications to basically that
people to make sure they're not bots
um
so you know you fill out the application
and basically
you will get access or maybe you won't
um we can't obviously get everybody in
for the beta but if you're interested
and excited that's another way you can
sort of get in on the bottom floor
um but yeah
we will launch as soon as we can launch
and we really need help um but
this kind of help is coming because so
many people are interested in
um you know getting around the
censorship they're seeing everywhere the
last few months have really proven our
model there's a lot of buzz about
pancreatic people are talking about it
constantly um and i really think we're
going to get not just to our funding
targets but far beyond that and really
get this thing running so there have
already been more than two million site
visits which is very heartening
yeah for for a social media uh
network that's not up yet that's pretty
impressive 3 500 donors 2 million visits
you know
100 and almost 180 k raised
and we are just kicking ass basically um
every time we go and work on this
application um it's changing and it's
growing and it's building and uh we're
doing all kinds of stuff that's really
um innovative
and we talk about it every month so the
other thing i think listeners and
viewers should know is that we do these
delivery meetings right we've had
transparency throughout this entire
process um so every month we do a
delivery meeting and we talk about the
um you know growth in the development
process what else we've been doing
around the project uh and we want to
make sure that people know our donors
know um that we're working day in day
out um you know to build this thing so
and i see that uh susie dawson the uh
creator of pan quick is in the chat room
so anybody if you want to uh ask
questions of susie
feel thr free her name is susie 3d
um and she's there if you want to uh
throw any questions her way
uh before i lose you uh john i i wanted
to uh also ask about world events um yes
sir i know we could we could talk about
it for hours but
uh
where do you see where do you see things
going right now with with ukraine
uh i don't see anything good on the
horizon i think that this is yet another
one of those situations that
you know every generation has one
where um the united states is perfectly
happy to pour
money and weapons into a situation
have it run as a proxy war um they know
the they know that the
that the ukrainians can't defeat the
russians but what they want to do is is
bog the russians down and you know that
that
tired old saying that the united states
is willing to fight to the last
ukrainian i think is actually true and
that's what makes it so sad so you know
the russians are going to end up
with the dunbas they're going to end up
with crimea they're going to probably
destroy
uh
mariupol and odessa it's gonna be
terrible there's gonna be loss of life
and then that's how it's gonna end
and so it's better to engage in some
sort of peace talks now even if you have
to put your tail between your legs and
give away something that you otherwise
wouldn't want to give away
otherwise look at look at the loss of
life that's on the horizon
so i'm really not optimistic you know
today president biden said
that um
that there is uh another
800 million
uh in weapons going to the ukrainians
this is the third tranche of 800 million
dollars in addition to the nearly 10
billion that we've already sent
well
is that what we're going to just do from
now on we're not going to spend money on
roads or schools or bridges or airports
uh we're going to spend it on weapons
for the for the ukrainians
and you notice you don't hear any uh
discussion discussions are urging of
peace talks from the bite administration
or from our government no in fact i
mentioned that today on my own show you
don't even hear the words peace talks
if you recall lee um
there there were
peace talks early on in istanbul the
united states of course didn't
participate it didn't even encourage the
uh ukrainians to attend
but they did they lasted three days
everybody went home and nobody's raised
the uh the idea again
yeah yeah
it it really is disgusting and there
seems to be no end in sight and the us
really seems to want it that way
i think i think they do
they don't like putin they never liked
putin he's independent he's not moldable
like yeltsin was uh he's not a friendly
like gorbachev was and so uh they
thought for a long time well we're just
gonna have to live with this guy even if
we don't like him but now they see an
opportunity where they don't have to
live with him
and they'll let the ukrainians do their
dirty work
can you postulate on what like
in the cia what the conversations are
right now what they're trying to achieve
i think i can i think that the
conversations in the cia cia are uh
probably focused on on training and
material and things like
secure communications
night vision goggles sniper rifles close
in stuff i think that they're that
they're doing two things number one it's
going to be a lot of paramilitary
training for the ukrainians and second
is a real focus on recruiting
uh access agents to the russian
leadership
that's what they're going to be focused
on
yeah um i also wanted to i saw you at an
event just uh
not too long ago we did another stand up
for assange event
and you know more more bad news coming
on that front uh the the latest hurdle
to having him extradited to be tortured
in the u.s they just passed the other
day and now i guess it goes to the home
secretary or something and and then it
went it went to the home secretary uh
yesterday uh preeti patel
uh she
is likely going to sign it julian's
attorneys have 14 days to appeal to the
uk supreme court they probably will but
all it's going to do is delay things for
14 days the only other thing and i i've
like i said the other night at the event
i've been accused of being
overly optimistic and i realized now
that i i was julian can still apply to
the european court of human rights he
can apply for relief
uh
there are three count em three
precedents where the european court of
human rights refused to allow the uk to
extradite to the u.s
people who had
um mental illnesses now julian is mildly
autistic
and he suffers from chronic depression
and anxiety
other prisoners
were not extradited because they had the
same maladies
and the european court of human rights
believed that the us practice of
solitary confinement was enough to push
them to attempt suicide
the problem that julian has now
is that the uk government said he's
perfectly free to appeal to the european
court of human rights that doesn't mean
that we have to put the brakes on the
extradition while his appeal is being
heard
so that defeats the whole purpose of the
appeal
wow okay yeah
um
i know some of you have already heard
some
some people watching this maybe have
already heard you uh
get give the speech about what kind of
trial julian will get in the united
states uh but i think most of them
probably have not yet heard that and
i i would like to ask you again you know
what kind of trial uh julian would get
once he's extradited to the united
states because you went through this
atrocious process as a whistleblower
revealing our torture program and so
what what kind of court
proceedings will those be
yeah you know this is really an awful
thing uh julian uh would be tried in the
eastern district of virginia that's the
federal court that covers the cia and
the pentagon
i'll i'll tell you
as it relates to julian exactly what my
jury consultant told me
his jury is going to be made up of
people who work for or who have friends
and relatives who work for the cia
the pentagon
the fbi the department of homeland
security and
intelligence community contractors
beltway bandits my jury consultant told
me if we were in any other district in
america i would say let's go for it
we're going to win but the eastern
district of virginia he said buddy you
don't have a prayer take the deal the
problem is and i said this last sunday
julian's not been offered a deal
yeah plea deal so we have a lot to worry
about with the eastern district i had a
judge notorious for reserving national
security uh cases for herself julian has
a different judge who's even worse than
mine because do you know what he did
before he was a judge in the eastern
district of virginia he was a judge in
the fisa court
the fisa which approves what 99 of all
far more than 99 i actually did the
research they approved 99.81
of all requests from the cia
yeah really looking out for our privacy
and our freedoms
not good at all
yeah and uh and as you've as you've
mentioned before they essentially
don't allow the uh the defendant to
bring forward any evidence yeah i'm glad
you raised that yes uh so they're going
to invoke something called sipa the
classified information protection act
uh
some of it is silly some of it is
important the silly stuff is
um they're going to physically seal the
courtroom with duct tape and plastic
sheeting right they'll take these big
plastic sheets like tarps and they'll
they'll put it over the um
the uh windows
and and seal the windows off so that the
russians can't beam a laser at the at
the window and read the vibrations and
and hear what's going on in the
courtroom uh they duct tape around the
uh
the door they play white no white noise
in the vestibule so nobody outside can
hear what's going on inside the
courtroom and then whenever they think
that someone might mention something
that maybe could possibly be classified
they do two things one they clear the
courtroom so the only people allowed in
the courtroom are the judge
the jury the bailiff the clerk
the lawyers and the defendant that's it
and then
even the jury's not allowed to hear the
classified information so in advance
the prosecutors and the judge will
determine what's classified and they'll
replace those words with unclassified
words for example this is going to sound
stupid but it's the honest to god's
truth
let's say
that they want to say well julian
released information that inside the cia
we call vault seven
well the words vault seven those are
classified
so
they're gonna say
instead of vault seven we use the words
swimming pool oh my god then they're
going to say your honor julian assange
released documents called swimming pool
that are very highly classified
well they're going to go through the
whole trial like that as if a jury could
analyze that well the jury gets a little
a little uh
cheat sheet of what means what
but they can't talk about it and they
can't take it out with them but the
thing is is when you tell the jury
listen these individual words are so
highly classified that you can't even
hear them with your ears we have to
block them from your ears they're going
to say my god this guy's guilty right
he's so guilty we can't even hear the
words
that he's accused of releasing
so the deck is stacked he doesn't have a
prayer
that's why i said sunday it's up to us
to be there in that courtroom every day
till they throw us out when they invoke
sipa we need to be out in front and you
know that every media outlet in the
world is going to be out in front we
need to be giving interviews in support
of him we have to write op-eds we have
to blow whistles if that's all that you
can do we have to do everything we can
to support him and to show that he is
not alone we are there and this is the
side of righteousness
yeah yeah uh
i i mean it's getting to that point
where all that's left is uh his feet in
the streets uh that's it because
everything has been exhausted yeah
that's great
uh well john and sean thank you so much
for taking the time to join me um
one more time can you just uh let people
know how they can support pan quake
sure uh go out to penn quick dot com
slash donate or just pancreate.com and
click on donate um and please you know
help us get across the finish line this
is the last phase of funding that we're
in right now it's going to help us get
to support people to have real human
support and so on um so we want to make
sure we have that in place so we can
serve you and give you that free
information system
with actual flowing information like the
kind of stuff john just said um allowed
to be said and shared on social
that's it thanks again thanks both of
you
thank you see you soon thanks
there they are shawn and john uh
about talking about pan quick talking
about so much more than that and you
know most of the other information we
covered is stuff that if pan quick
were uh fully operational right now you
could talk about it on there and not
fear that your channels are going to be
canceled that you're all
all your videos are going to be banned
globally like mine are uh
eight years worth you know not not fear
that you're going to be put into a
filter bubble uh you know like my tweets
are where i can tweet something out and
if it's got too many dirty words like
terrorism or uh or cia in it then they
won't actually show the tweet to anyone
so
that's the goal we got to build up the
alternatives while we continue to fight
um i have another story for you here
before we wrap up
and
then i'm also going to tell you about my
brand new show
which i hope you will support
um
but first
uh
here you know biden's uh
biden's approval ratings are like the
lowest they've ever been even in even in
this [__] trumped up proxy war that
we're in the middle of he's still
normally during a war during a u.s
backed war during a proxy war the u.s
president is able to uh push enough
propaganda to say hey everybody get
behind me yeah you're my
we need to all get together on this but
biden seems to be failing even at that
uh despite how heavy the propaganda's
been which has been insane it's
wall-to-wall i mean i don't know if you
guys turn on those mainstream channels
but it is wall-to-wall
let's keep arming ukrainians rather than
ever talking about peace anyway approval
not doing well so
i guess he he and his administration
have decided well let's
do some things that sound as if we might
do a little bit of the maybe sort of
kind of the things that we promised
during uh the campaign for the
presidency
and so
this is uh just the other day
this is
cbs news reporting this
changes to student which explains why
they're so excited about
something that is not
as big a deal as they act like changes
to student loan programs could bring
millions closer to getting out of debt
education department says oh my god
they're going to do it they're going to
get everybody out of debt this is
incredible well what what what what are
they doing here the education department
announces fixes on tuesday yeah
good luck announcing fixes to the
united states right now fixes on tuesday
to multiple student loan programs giving
thousands of borrowers immediate relief
from student loan debt and bringing
millions more years closer to having
their student loans
i don't know why they wrote it that way
millions more years closer to having
their student loans forgiven
it comes as the buy administration
continues to examine canceling student
loan debt for millions of americans just
that line drives me nuts examine
we we we're gonna have a meeting to
write a paper on maybe considering
canceling a couple of uh student loan
debts um
it's
honestly like
i i wrote an article a while back on how
biden could actually cancel student loan
debt federal debt immediately like he
could sign a piece of paper and it'd be
over
uh but they're not going to do that
right because they like having people in
debt they like forcing people into uh
you know the the into wage slavery in a
way that they don't necessarily want uh
having people in debt not just makes
billions of dollars for
so many different industries but it also
helps keep people under control people
are not they're generally not fighting
back they're generally not in the
streets if they have crushing debt uh
and we have a debt bubble in multiple
regards we have auto debt bubble we have
a student loan debt bubble we have a
housing debt bubble um
so
those things are all are all good for
our economy that runs on debt
the changes are being made to public
service loan forgiveness programs and
the income driven payment plans
according to the education department
the fixes will give 40 000 borrowers
immediate forgiveness and bring at least
3.6 million borrowers closer to relief
by at least three years through income
driven repayments
uh
and here's a quote student loans were
never meant to be a life sentence they
love saying beautiful things like this
but it certainly felt the way that way
for borrowers locked out of debt relief
uh that they're eligible for but you'll
notice that
they're given like 15 different steps
that you could maybe have some of your
debt forgiven
and it's like
[__] get rid of it [__] wipe it
off the books
that he could do that tomorrow not to
mention this [__] should never cost this
crazy amounts of money to begin with
in other countries they give their
people educated university education for
free
here in the united states you've got to
give an arm and a limb and a
semen donation and a [__] blood drive
you gotta
like
it's insane what people have to pay just
to go to school and especially if they
want to go to the best schools because
they want to be up for the best jobs
uh
tens of thousands of dollars you know
people often graduate with a hundred
thousand
in student loan debt
and if they wanted to do anything that
isn't one of these big money jobs if
they want to do anything that's not a
hedge funder or a [__] banker or a
you know a lobbyist they want to do
something that's not one of those things
then they'll never pay it off they'll
they'll be paying this debt for the rest
of their lives which keeps them poor
which is good for the system largely
good for the system
um
and it's like
biden's been in office how long and he
said he was gonna he he he floated the
idea of
erasing student loan debt and here we
are
over a year into his
administration and it's
it's uh
maybe we're gonna we're gonna with a few
people will get some forgiveness some of
the time if they can prove that they
hate their lives
um
seeing if there's anything else useful
in here
the experts announced tuesday come as
the biden administration has already
canceled more than 17 billion dollars in
debt from
for some 725 000 borrowers since
president biden took office uh that's
not really true it's largely small
cancellations it's not
he largely is not
like saved people's lives from crushing
debt
um
but you'll also notice this says
something about our media right our
media
they're in the job of joe biden
promotion
that is their job to
sit here and say
oh look at what a good job he's doing
how great he's doing i mean so that was
cbs news how many articles in the years
since biden got into office how many
articles has cbs news ran on how biden
hasn't done [__] on student loan debt
probably zero
so that'll show you that simply by the
choice even if that were an accurately
written article simply by the choice of
well we're not going to highlight the
fact that biden's done nothing on
student loan debt and instead we're
going to wait until they've done
something a little here's a little
[__] piece meal
yeah we're going to give you a little
bit a little crumb
then we'll write an article biden giving
crumbs to people
so that tells you something about the
media they're like cbs uh
they're
in the job of joe biden promotion
um and and that's not what your media
should be
your media should be
largely adversarial to the dominant
controlling class
to the people that have all the airwaves
that you know biden can stand up on a uh
podium well maybe he can't stand up he
he could kind of stand up with three
people helping him and someone you know
pushing from behind and maybe some like
uh strings coming down from having one
of those suits like when you see like a
peter pan in a play
he'll just lower him down with strings
attached and you know maybe and give a
uh a speech um
but anyway buying this stand they give a
speech it'll be covered to all of
america there'll be countless articles
written about this so that's how easy it
is for him to get his message out there
the idea of the press the point of the
press
should be to cover the things that don't
automatically get all of the coverage
and could be critical about them and dig
into them and dig into the reality not
do what [__] cbs and the other
mainstream media allies do which is give
a fawning propaganda show
for your ruling elite and even fox news
which obviously they'll spend every
episode attacking joe biden that's their
job but they won't attack the system as
a whole they won't go after capitalism
they won't go after
corporate america for the most part
they'll just go after joe biden because
their job then fox news is as important
in it as
cbs and the others
uh their job is to make you think that
there is some kind of massive difference
between the two sides the republicans
and democrats well you turn on fox news
and they hate you by and you turn on cnn
msnbc they love joe biden so clearly
these are two very different things yeah
look at what they're not talking about
think about what they're not talking
about what is not on the agenda okay
it's most of the us foreign policy
it's
the the capitalism as a whole which is
all of our lives how it's set up wage
slavery uh it's it's the environmental
destruction
uh you could just go down the list for
an hour on everything they don't talk
about and how it's largely the most
important stuff in our lives
uh it's
truly incredible
all right well i want to wrap up here by
telling you about my new show
it's going to be called
uh
the most censored news with lee camp
and it's going to be
online uh shorter episodes um three to
four days a week
and it's gonna be kind of like it won't
have correspondence so it won't be much
like the second half of a redacted
tonight episode but it'll be a lot like
the first half of a redacted tonight
episode
not in a uh
a giant news studio maybe but otherwise
same writing research
passion jokes
images
clips all that stuff everything you got
from kind of that first half are
redacted tonight and it'll be called the
most censored news with lee camp and
it's done i'm doing it in uh
coordination with uh you know it's made
possible by mint press and behind the
headlines uh men pressing behind the
head like behind the headlines is mint
press's uh video platform that they uh
have created
and
here's the thing though it can only
happen if their fundraising campaign is
successful um
that's the deal we've made that this
show will exist if their fundraising
campaign is successful
and so i'm gonna put the link in the uh
comment section i'm also going to play
their fundraising video for you
uh because it's also interesting even if
you are even if you're not in a position
that you can uh can help out their
fundraiser i think you'll enjoy watching
the video
so
uh manar adley is who you'll see uh
hosting the the video it's just a few
minutes long um
i think six or ten minutes long or
something
minora adley is who you see uh hosting
the video she's the creator the founder
and editor-in-chief of mint press mint
press you've probably hopefully heard of
one of the best outlets out there
independent uh not owned by corporate
clowns not owned by corporate america
not owned and sponsored by the the
biggest [__] villains in the world uh
truly independent site that does
impressive work uh has people like dan
cohen and uh alan mcleod and publishes
chris hedges articles and uh so much
more
so
i'm gonna show you that video uh but
also i hope you are able to uh to join
in the fundraising fundraising campaign
it's at indiegogo you can also just
search for uh
mint press and behind the headlines at
indiegogo.com
um
but uh uh
what was i about to say
oh there's a bunch of great perks there
as well if you sign up you get tote bags
and things like that
um
so
here we go and i'll wrap up the show
after this video
hey everyone i'm minar adley founder and
editor-in-chief of midpress news and
director of our new video project behind
the headlines i have an urgent appeal to
make to everyone who cares not only for
our first amendment but for the future
of our planet independent watchdog
journalism that holds the military class
accountable is under threat with the war
in ukraine raging on and corporate media
outlets pushing a pro-war agenda we've
entered war time where having access to
alternative information to the war
machine is crucial to preventing
escalation the nuclear arms race is not
a joke we're experiencing an
unprecedented amount of censorship
unlike anything we've seen before
just the last month independent anti-war
journalists have been targeted in an
organized smear campaign d-platformed
outright purged off of social media
platforms and even given state
affiliated labels on their accounts
youtube has deleted hundreds of
thousands of historical videos for
prominent anti-war journalists and
figures including abby martin chris
hedges and lee camp and is demonetizing
political content everywhere to hit our
bank accounts our very own fundraisers
on gofundme were just taken down without
reason and an opportunity to appeal and
this doesn't even include the past five
years of being algorithmically shadow
banned and targeted by big tech
these are the modern day book burners
they are trying to discredit the work of
the most important dissenting voices of
our time they want to cause division and
censor any information that challenges
the corporate and military
establishments agenda they want war to
fill the bank accounts of the executives
at raytheon and lockheed martin for the
last several years mint press has been
at the forefront of sounding the alarm
about the deep state working with
silicon valley tech giants like google
facebook and twitter to control the free
flow of information and your news feed
to ensure any sort of alternative
information or narrative to the
establishment algorithmically disappears
we are nowhere near backing down because
the future of our planet and the
prosperity of peace and justice depend
on our reporting this is why i've
partnered up with the media freedom
foundation and project censored to
create a new video reporting project
called behind the headlines to help us
build this project we will need your
support we need to raise four hundred
thousand dollars in the next year so
we're creating our first phase
fundraiser to be stated for two hundred
thousand and it's just a two month
campaign the goal here is to create a
video platform that is 100
people funded a non-profit video
platform with the most important
dissenting names in independent media
that have felt the brunt of this
censorship campaign we're working with
political comedian lee camp and
filmmaker and investigative journalist
dan cohen our board includes fbi
whistleblower colleen rowley
international human rights attorney todd
pierce and president of the media
freedom foundation the director of
project censored himself mickey huff lee
camp is from a long line of political
comedians from george carlin to bill
hicks we're giving him a platform with
full editorial freedom to write and
produce his own political comedy lee
camp shows are like a form of
investigative comedy they give the
audience something to think about
regarding key issues of the day that are
often distorted in the establishment
pressed or ignored all together
given the many challenges we face from
the climate crisis forever wars and the
global pandemic it's important to laugh
when and how we can otherwise we'd have
to just wail and cry
lee blends wit and dark humor with
quality reporting that is truly a call
to action
dan cohen is a jack of all trades he's
an investigative journalist based in
washington dc reporting from the belly
of the beast he's currently working on
several gorilla style documentaries
where he traveled to the heart of
conflicts targeted by u.s imperialism
and corporate pillaging the first is a
three-part series about a revolution in
formation in haiti another is about the
failures of the peace accords in
colombia another about resistance in
gaza and israel's temple movement and
their plans to destroy al-aqsa as part
of an end of times prophecy
all of these issues trace back to the
u.s empire and its plots to create and
maintain instability around the world
now in addition to the documentaries and
written investigations dan is also
leading our video investigative series
called behind the headlines he has
exposed how corporate media is in bed
with the pentagon the vitamin
administration and much much more for
far too long some of the best and most
important dissenting journalists have
been forced to turn to foreign state
media to produce the most groundbreaking
watchdog journalism because the us
legacy media has completely failed the
public it specializes in producing fast
food news that is sensationalized
divisive working as a mouthpiece for the
two-party duopoly weapons manufacturers
like lockheed martin and raytheon and
hawkish think tanks that are directly
funded by nato
we don't have a watchdog media anymore
we have an extremist corporate media
beating the drums of war so we can't
rely on the legacy media in our own
country to tell us what exactly is
happening at home and around the world
we shouldn't have to go to foreign state
media outlets to fill up most polls
either it's time that we create our own
and become the media the truth is we
can't keep waiting for the oligarchy to
give us a media that represents we the
people it's time we unite on a broader
front of nonpartisanship that holds the
elite accountable the way journalism is
defined by our first amendment to revive
the fourth estate and create our very
own media that goes behind the headlines
it's time that we put our money where
our mouths are because our first
amendment and its free press free speech
principles are all on life support to
help us build this project we will need
your support we have to raise four
hundred thousand dollars in the next
year so we're going to start with this
two 200 000 first phase fundraiser for
the next two months and here's what it's
going to support
lee camp's new weekly political comedy
show the most censored news with lee
camp and we're completing four
documentaries by dan cohen end game
apocalypse inside israel's temple mount
movement and its plans to destroy
al-aqsa mosque israel's may 2021 mega
assault on gaza and the armed resistance
that won the war
inside colombia's narco state and
diabolical plot between the dea and
colombian government to plunge the
country in a state of civil war and
finally we're wrapping up a three-part
series inside haiti's rising resistance
movement against neoliberalism and u.s
occupation and how the u.s is trying to
quash it we're also launching a monthly
behind the headlines report project
investigative video series with dan
cohen covering the military industrial
complex how propaganda works and much
more we're also launching a weekly video
podcast interview series with myself
monarch adley i hope that you will join
us today
[Music]
cool
hope you hope you enjoyed that uh that
uh
i put the link in there you can go to
indiegogo.com and just type in behind
the headlines you should find it uh hold
on one second i'll put the link in one
more time in the comment section
and uh
yeah
i know it sounds like a lot of money but
uh obviously these are these are big
projects they're talking about that
involve a lot of people
and a lot of employees uh
but you know if you're able to give five
dollars that's that's usually what ends
up making these things possible is a
uh you know a thousand people or ten
thousand people or whatever giving five
bucks so
thank you for your help and if that
fundraiser is successful then
there will be a new comedy show to
replace redacted tonight it'll be
different it won't be identical but
it'll be close and i and you like always
hopefully we'll keep fighting
talk soon